<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matrix Profile Foundation (Posts by Matrix Profile Foundation)</title><link>https://matrixprofile.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://matrixprofile.org/authors/matrix-profile-foundation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:nowhere@mail.com"&gt;Matrix Profile Foundation&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:40:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Meet Yue Lu</title><link>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-yue-lu/</link><dc:creator>Matrix Profile Foundation</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Yue Lu" src="https://matrixprofile.org/images/yue.jpg" style="max-width: 300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Matrix Profile Foundation is excited to partner, this summer, with two UCR researchers who will help expand the quality and functionality of our codebases! Yue Lue and Kaveh Kamgar bring a wealth of valuable experience that will serve the Matrix Profile community well. In this post, learn a little bit more about Yue and her time with MPF!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introduce who you are/your current role at UCR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Yue Lu. I am a first-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the University of California, Riverside. Before joining UCR, I received my B.S. degree in Software Technology and Application (with First Class Honors) from Macau University of Science and Technology in 2018. I am now working with Dr. Eamonn Keogh on time-series mining. My research interests include data mining, time-series analysis and deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What you like about your Ph.D. program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ph.D. program at UCR provides me with an excellent opportunity to work with Dr. Eamonn Keogh, an eminent and knowledgable professor in the field of data mining. His research works give me a new insight into how to deal with problems effectively. (In some cases, it's possible that simple ideas can work as well as or even outperform fancy &amp;amp; complex methods.) I believe that by working with him, I can gain a great deal of knowledge and experience different from my undergraduate study. This is what I am excited most about for my Ph.D. program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Possible projects that you'll work on with the MPF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The projects that I’ll work on with the MPF will be involved in snippets and discords. For the first few weeks, I will write a tutorial on snippets for MPF community members, explaining the principle and usage of the snippets algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What excites you about the MPF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a beginner in time-series mining. Working with the MPF is a great chance for me to learn about the matrix profile and its related works, so I am very grateful and excited to be part of this team. Hopefully, I will be of some help to make the Matrix Profile better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meet-the-team</category><guid>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-yue-lu/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Meet Jackson Green</title><link>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-jackson-green/</link><dc:creator>Matrix Profile Foundation</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Jackson Green" src="https://matrixprofile.org/images/jack.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is your personal &amp;amp; professional background?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was interested in computers and technology from a very young age, I started teaching myself the basic tools for web design and development in high school and took all the classes they offered on the subject. I followed this passion to college where I received a B.S. in Computer Science, as well as a B.A. in Theatre. Right after graduating in 2018 I started work as a Software Developer at CRST International, where I continue creating in house web applications and web page design specifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did you get connected with the Matrix Profile and MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well working at CRST I met Tyler Mars, who asked me if I would be willing to design a logo for an open source project he was working on at the time. After creating a logo, he asked me to make a website showcasing the people who had been working on that project, and after some time they asked me to join the team and be responsible for maintaining the design of the web site and branding materials. That open source project was MPF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you do at MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I oversee the website design, logo, and brand colors. The title we landed on Chief Design Officer, which I really like, but probably means you see my name on any commits to the organization’s main libraries… for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What excites you about the future of Matrix Profile and the MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am new to the matrix profile as a whole, so the thing that excites me most is learning more about it. I have been shown how useful a tool like this can be in so many different areas, and I can’t wait for it to reach its full potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meet-the-team</category><guid>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-jackson-green/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Meet Francisco Bischoff</title><link>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-francisco-bischoff/</link><dc:creator>Matrix Profile Foundation</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Francisco Bischoff" src="https://matrixprofile.org/images/francisco.jpg" style="max-width: 300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is your personal &amp;amp; professional background?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a medical doctor specialized in Imunohemoteraphy. I'm a computer enthusiast since childhood and learned to program when I was about 15 yo. I have a Master in Medical Informatics and currently enrolled in a PhD for Health Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did you get connected with the Matrix Profile and MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my MSc. I've started to study deeply time-series and looking for new methods. That's when I crossed with some Eammon's papers and after some e-mail exchanges, I got hooked by The Matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you do at MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm working in the R language branch in MPF with the tsmp package, as well as being involved with the API design and implementing low-level algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What excites you about the future of Matrix Profile and the MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see great potential in time-series data mining through the matrix profile. The MPF was a great achievement and will help to push the matrix profile to new boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meet-the-team</category><guid>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-francisco-bischoff/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Meet Andrew Van Benschoten</title><link>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-andrew-van-benschoten/</link><dc:creator>Matrix Profile Foundation</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Andrew Van Benschoten" src="https://matrixprofile.org/images/andrew.jpg" style="max-width: 300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is your personal &amp;amp; professional background?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a recovering academic: I earned my Bachelors degree in Biology from MIT, then went to the University of California - San Francisco for a Ph.D in Biophysics. I graduated in 2015, right when data science was emerging as the hot new career in Silicon Valley. Since my thesis leveraged a significant amount of computational biology it seemed like a perfect fit, and I joined the Insight Data Science Fellows program to help with my transition. From there I went to Oracle (digital advertising), Target (data measurement &amp;amp; telemetry plus lots of DevOps) and am now the Head of Data Science at Ovative Group (back to digital advertising).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did you get connected with the Matrix Profile and MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Target, Frankie and I worked on a team responsible for detecting anomalies across thousands of disparate time series, from key business metrics to server farm performance stats. This led us to discover the Matrix Profile and ultimately open-source the original matrixprofile-ts library. This then led to subsequent connections with other authors of matrix profile implementations. After a few months of working together we decided to make things more official and form a cohesive, unified group known as the Matrix Profile Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you do at MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I play the role of CEO on our leadership board.: My primary job is to facilitate development of MPF's vision &amp;amp; direction, and then identify the right strategy to get us there. However, I'm also an organizational nerd which means I double as our unofficial Scrum Master. And I still do a little Python programming wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What excites you about the future of Matrix Profile and the MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Data is only getting bigger. We're just scratching the surface of IoT and connected applications, which means that there will be a massive need for high-performing algorithms both now and in the future. I'm a little biased, but I think there's a 5% chance that Matrix Profile will be the "next big thing" in Data Science, and I'm excited to help bring that to fruition. It's also been a great experience being a part of the broader Open Source community and engaging with so many fascinating applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meet-the-team</category><guid>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-andrew-van-benschoten/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Meet Frankie Cancino</title><link>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-frankie-cancino/</link><dc:creator>Matrix Profile Foundation</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Frankie Cancino" src="https://matrixprofile.org/images/frankie.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is your personal &amp;amp; professional background?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did my undergrad at the University of Missouri earning a B.S. in Information Technology and Computer Science with a minor in Business. After graduating from Mizzou, I started off my professional career at Target in their Data Sciences organization then moving to an analytics team. While working at Target I began earning my M.S. from the University of Minnesota in Analytics. In addition to working at Target and earning a Master's, I founded and organize the Data Science Minneapolis Meetup group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did you get connected with the Matrix Profile and MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally found out about the Matrix Profile while working at Target and worked with Andrew to open-source the library matrixprofile-ts. Eventually, joining the Matrix Profile Foundation to oversee applied work and use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you do at MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides some day-to-day tasks, I primarily look for partnerships and applied use cases with the matrix profile libraries being maintained by the MPF. I've also presented about using the matrix profile for various use cases across the U.S. and Canada. The others branded me as "CIO", to make me sound more official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What excites you about the future of Matrix Profile and the MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What excites me most, is the potential and usefulness of this research. I'm consistently looking for ways to get a better perspective of my data. This helps me evaluate the effectiveness of models and their results across various use cases. Also, I believe the MPF can help standardize the matrix profile libraries and see to it that they reach their full potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meet-the-team</category><guid>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-frankie-cancino/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Meet Tyler Marrs</title><link>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-tyler-marrs/</link><dc:creator>Matrix Profile Foundation</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tyler Marrs" src="https://matrixprofile.org/images/tyler.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is your personal &amp;amp; professional background?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out creating websites at the young age of 12 and started working as a software engineer after earning my bachelor's degree. Falling into genomics research by accident led me down the path of obtaining a master's degree in software engineering and starting a doctoral degree in informatics. However, the doctoral degree was not for me, so I dropped the program and started working as a data scientist. My practical experience working in genomics made it a pretty smooth transition as I was already familiar with distributed algorithms, big data, and statistical programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How did you get connected with the Matrix Profile and MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD) conference in 2017 is where I first learned about the Matrix Profile; Eamonn Keogh and Abdullah Muenn presented. The talk seemed interesting, as the research problems I worked on were mostly time-series specific. At the time, no public repositories existed for the algorithms, so I started implementing my own with intentions on creating an open-source library. However, Andrew beat me to creating a public repository. So instead of creating a new library and competing with Andrew, I started to contribute to his repository instead. We eventually started frequently chatting online and decided to see if other matrix profile related libraries wanted to help establish the "Matrix Profile Foundation." Franz, Andrew, Austin, and I all saw great potential in this venture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you do at MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm the primary contributor to the Python library "matrixprofile." Additionally, I oversee technical decisions. We do our best to simplify concepts and keep the library aligned with our mission statement of accessibility. If you want to give me a label, "CTO" would be the correct one to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What excites you about the future of Matrix Profile and the MPF?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of untapped potentials out there, and I feel that we are just opening the door to everyone. The biggest challenge with very dense research is making it accessible and easily understandable to everyone. I think that we have done a pretty good job at closing that gap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meet-the-team</category><guid>https://matrixprofile.org/posts/meet-tyler-marrs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>